Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - General Documents
    - letters re: Beza Mahazfaly, WWF and Barthelemi Vaohita Location: Paris, Gland, Antananarivo, Beza Mahafaly, 1978; letters (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Guy Ramanantsoa, Alison Richard, AJ, Jean Jacques Petter,
    - Philip Ndegwa proposal to RJ on economics of environment in Kenya Author: Philip Ndegwa Kenya, 1975; letter (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Peasants are poor but few starve Author: Richard and Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1979?; newspaper articles (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fauna Preservation Society Author: J. Ratsirarson Location: Madagascar, 1978; letter (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Colloque Scientifique International sur les Lemuriens, Academie Malagache Location: Antananarivo, 1978; letters and reports (Box 2, Folder 15)
      AJ, Guy Ramanantsoa, Albignac, Buettner-Janush, JJ Petter,
    - list of UNESCO and other frestry Aid programs Location: Madagascar, 1979; notes (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Colloque Internationale sur les Lemuriens Location: Antananarivo, 1978; handwritten notes (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Colloque Scientifique Internationale sur les Lemuriens Location: Antananarivo, 1978; papers (Box 2, Folder 16)
      A Protection des Lemuriens, Andriamapianina, AJ, Conservation in Madagascar, project de conservation de l'aye-aye,
    - Tom Lovejoy letters Location: Antananarivo, 1975; letters (Box 2, Folder 16)
      letters to and from Tom Lovejoy including important letter on Malagasy attitudes and complaints
    - minutes of meeting at WWF Location: Gland, Switzerland, 1978; report and letter (Box 2, Folder 16)
      minutes of meeting Mar 8th 1978, which decided no or few funds for Beza Mahafaly, but instead to fund WWF Madagascar, Rep. Barthelmi Vaohita, Alison Richard, Robert Sussman, Lucas Hoffmann, AJ, David Munro, Pierre Portas
    - A World Like our Own, 1975; handwritten notes (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Failed attempt to provide textbook on Malagasy biodiversity for Malagasy Schools Location: Madagascar, 1970s; letters (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Russ Mittermeier, Tom Lovejoy, Guy Rahanantsoa
    - Failed attempt notes Location: Madagascar, 1970s; handwritten notes (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Reunion Tour Location: Madagascar and Mauritius, 1981; letters and notes (Box 2, Folder 18)
      AJ, detective story draft where Alison Jolly kills them off, Letter to Gerald and Lee Durrell where Alison Jolly describes the tour for real.
    - 1980 Study with Bill Oliver and Sheila O'Connor of Jersey, 1980; letters (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Guy Ramanantsoa, Barthelemi Vaohita, Cesaire Rabenoro, Bob and Linda Sussman, Cyril Dalais
    - IUCN proposed WWF program in Mad. Under Barthelemi Vaohita Location: Madagascar, 1980; letters and notes (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Alison Richard report on Beza Mahafaly Location: Madagascar, 1981; report (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Bob Sussman, Tom Lovejoy, Alison Richard, Report on visit to Madagascar in association with the project "A Preliminary Program of Conservation in Madagascar"
    - Anthony Mence, Conservation Monitoring Centre, Cambridge Location: Madagascar, 1981; letter and report (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Barthelemi Vaohita visit and discussion of program.
    - WWF, Barthelemi Vaohita distributed World like our own Location: Madagascar, 1981; letters (Box 2, Folder 18)
      AJ, Jeremy Lester, Pierre Portas
    - I think I have been here before Author: AMKB Location: Ithaca, 1978; letters (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Advice not to publish Morris Bishop biography
    - Mike Curtis Atlantic Monthly Location: Ithaca, 1960-70s; letters (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Morris Bishop biography
    - Lucy's Legacy reviews and notices Location: Princeton, 1990s; letters and notes (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Harvard University Press, C. Stuart Hall, Donna Haraway comments on woman chapter, book poems, University of Chicago Press, Adrian Barnett
    - Ringtailed Lemur Biology Location: Lewes, 2005; Consent form, letter, book jacket (Box 2, Folder 19)
      permissions letters
    - Yale University Press, World Like our Own Location: Madagascar, 1980; letters (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Macmillan, Evolution of Primate Behaviour 2nd ed. Location: Rockefeller, 1980-90; letters and notes (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Evolution of Primate Behaviour, 1st edition Location: Lewes, 1974; letters (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Gustav Fischer Verlag Stuttgart
    - Play Location: Lewes, 1977; letters (Box 2, Folder 19)
      penguin books, pergamon press
    - Assorted Reviews of other people's books, 1970-2000; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - London Review of Books Location: Lewes, 2001-09; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - National Geographic Location: Princeton, 1965-1994; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - New Scientist Location: Princeton, 1986; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - New Society Location: Lewes, 1976; letter (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Smithsonian Magazine, Consciousness in Animals Location: Rockefeller, 1970s-80s; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - TREE Location: Princeton, 1990-1; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Trends in Ecology and Evolution
    - UNESCO Location: Paris, 1988-9; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Woodland Park Zoo Location: Chicago, 1990; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - World Bank Location: Washington, 1990; letters (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - key environment Location: Madagascar, 1980s; letters (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Paulien, John Teherne, Philippe Oberle, Albignac, charles blanc, Vaohitra
    - Science - front cover Location: Yale, 1962; magazine cover (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Puppet, Eulemur fulvus photographed by John Buettner-Janusch on Alison Jolly head
    - Lemur Study links social life to evolution of intelligence' Location: Berenty, 1966; newspaper articles (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - scientist says intelligence began in south east asia', 1966; newspaper article (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Animal Life Location: Madagascar, 1969; magazine (Box 5, Folder 1)
      lemurs
    - Malagasy lemurs - clues to our Past draft Location: Berenty, 1970; typed article (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lemur Expedition Newsletter Location: Berenty, Fort Dauphin, article (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lemur Social Behaviour and Primate Intelligence Location: Berenty, 1966; article (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Diary of Cornwall trip for Torrey Canyon article Location: Cornwall, 196?; typed notes and article (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Animal Kingdom
    - Madagascar Times report Location: Madagascar, 1974; newspaper article (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Peasants are poor but few starve Author: RJ and Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1978; newspaper article (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "One-Eye was dying" Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1978; typed draft (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Draft of smithsonian article, So me tell tails
    - Shrinking Forests still teem with wildlife Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1978; newspaper article, photocopied (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Where Marxist socialism has a gentler face Author: Nicholas Ashford Location: Madagascar, Newspaper article, photocopied (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - English Avocets Animal ingdom Author: Alison Jolly Havergate Nature Reserve, 1969; typed notes and letters (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - The Study of Lemur Social Behaviour Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1970; typed notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Texts for Tananarive conference on the rational use and conservation of nature
    - An Apparent Lunar Periodicity in the Sexual Cycle of Certain Prosimians Author: Ursula Cowgill, R.J. Cowgill, G.E. Hutchinson, Alison Bishop Location: Yales, 1962; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Osborn Zoological Laboratory, Yale, A nice idea, but ignoring the olfactory synchronization of oestrus, so it was more like one case than many.
    - Control of the Hand in Lower Primates Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1962; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Science 102
    - Use of the Hand in Lower Primates Author: Alison Bishop Location: Yale, 1962; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
      J. Buettner-Janusch, Evolutionary and Genetic Biology of the Primates
    - Choice of Cue in Prosimian Learning Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Animal Behaviour 12
    - Prosimians Manipulation of Simple Object Problems Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1964; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Lemur Social Behaviour and Primate Intelligence Author: Alison Bishop Location: Berenty, 1966; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Science 153
    - Malagasy lemurs - clues to our past Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1967; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Animal Kingdom 70
    - A Handbook of Living Primates Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1968; book review (Box 5, Folder 2)
      J. R. Napier, P.H.Napier
    - Observations on Galago crassicaudatus sent to B.G.F. Sauer Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, Zambia, 1966; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cycles Genitaux Saisonnieres de Mammiferes Sauvages (R. Canivenc, ed.) Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1968; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 2)
      This book has a fundamental and much neglected paper by Arlette Petter on birth seasons
    - The Soul of the Ape Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1969; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Eugene Marais
    - The Stability of Territorial Boundaries in a Lemur Troop Author: Alison Jolly and P.H. Klopper Berenty, 1970; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Folia primat. 12
    - Troop Continuity and troop spacing in Propithecus verreauxi and lemur catta at Berenty Author: AJ Berenty, 1972; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Folia primat.17
    - Hour of Birth in Primates and Man Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1972; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Folia primat 18
    - Primate Birth Hour Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1973; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      International Zoo Yearbook 13
    - The Study of Primate Infancy Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1974; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Infant Competence, J.S. Bruner, K. Connolly
    - Population, espace vital et composition des groupes chez le maki et le sifaka Author: AJ, Gustafson, Mertl, Ramanantsoa Berenty, 1975; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Berenty, Bull. Acad. Malgache
    - Lemur behaviour and Populations Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1978; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Population Control by Social Behaviour, F.J Ebling, D.M Stoddart, Institute of Biology
    - Conservation in Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1978; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Nature 275
    - Frustrating search for the monkey with a lion's tail Author: Alison Jolly Location: India, western Ghats, 1979; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Smithsonian 10(8)
    - Comparative Ecology and Behaviour of Primates Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1971; book review (Box 5, Folder 3)
      R.P Michael, J.H. Crook
    - The Study of Prosimian Behaviour Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1979; book review (Box 5, Folder 3)
      G.A. Doyle, R.D. Martin
    - Beyond the Green Revolution Author: Alison Jolly and RJ Location: Lewes, 1979; book review (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Tenrecs Author: AJ Lewes, 1970s?; Book Review (Box 5, Folder 3)
      J.F. Eisenberg, E. Gould
    - The Chimpanzees' Tea Party, BBS Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1978; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Can't we have it both ways? Commentary on Parker and Gibson. BBS Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1979; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Aspects of the behaviour of the Sifaka Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1973; letter and review (typed) (Box 5, Folder 3)
      T.T. Struhsaker, Alison Richard
    - Man, the Promising Primate, Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1973; letter and review (typed) (Box 5, Folder 3)
      P.J. Wilson
    - The Aye-Aye of Madagascar (film) Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1972-3; letter and typed draft (Box 5, Folder 3)
      also Ghosts at the end of the Earth, David Attenborough,
    - Primate Studies Author: AJ Lewes, 1974; review (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Comparative Ecology and Behaviour of Primates, R.P. Michael, J.H. Crook, Science 184
    - Propithecus Verreauxi Population and Ranging at Berenty Author: AJ, H. Gustafson, W.L.R. Oliver, S.M. O'connor Berenty, 1982; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Population, troop spacing, reserve size, folia primatol 39
    - Population and Troop Ranges of Lemur Catta and Lemur fulvus at Berenty Author: AJ, W.L.R. Oliver, S.M. O'Connor Berenty, 1982; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Folia Primatol. 39
    - Island of the dodo is down to its last few native species Author: Alison Jolly Location: Mauritious, 1982; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Mauritius, Smithsonian 13 (7) 94-105
    - lemurs Author: AJ Madagascar, 1984; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Wildlife
    - The Puzzle of Female Feeding Priority Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rockefeller, 1984; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Female Primates, M.F. Small (ed)
    - The Evolution of Primate Behaviour Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rockefeller, 1985; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Amer. Scientist 73
    - Predatory Behaviour in captive lemur spp Author: Alison Jolly and W.L.R. Oliver Location: Durrell, Jersey, 1985; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Zoo Biology 4. It would be unethical today to give live prey to lemurs.
    - A new science that sees animals as conscious beings Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rockefeller, 1985; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Smithsonian 15(12) 66-81, Donald Griffin, Carolyn Ristau
    - Science fiction Author: AJ Princeton, 1986; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      New Scientist, Marcus chown, Greg Beer, W. Gibson
    - Lemur Survival Author: AJ Madagascar, 1986; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Primates: the road to self-sustaining populations, K. Benirschke
    - Meeting the Bizarre and Marvellous Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1987; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Country Life
    - Madagascar: A World Apart Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1987; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      National Geographic 171
    - The Evolution of Purpose Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1988; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Machiavellian Intelligence, A.Whiten, R. Byrne
    - Mad. Lemurs: On the edge of survival Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1988; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      National Geographic 174
    - The World's wild places Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1988; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      The Courier, UNESCO
    - The Madagascar Challenge: human needs and fragile eco systems Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1989; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Environmental and the poor: Development strategies for a common agenda, H.J. Leonard, Overseas development council, Washington DC pp.189-215
    - The Greenhouse Effect and Biological Diversity Author: Alison Jolly and D. Rubenstein Princeton, 1989; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Trends in Ecology and Evolution 4.3
    - The Natural History of the Gorilla Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1981; book review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      A.F. Dixon
    - Dennett's "Panglossian paradigm" Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1983; book review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Manwatching Author: AJ Princeton, 1980?; book review (typed draft) (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Desmond Morris
    - Malayan Primates, David Chivers (ed.) Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1980?; book review (typed draft) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Nocturnal Malagay Primates Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1980?; book review (typed draft) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Panglossian Paradigm Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1983; commentary, typed (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Dennett, Intentional systems in cognitive ethology, Behav. Brain. Sci.
    - Boiling down intelligence Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1980s; commentary, typed (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Euan Macphail, Princeton
    - Harsh times for Madagascar's growing numbers Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1988; newspaper article (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Daily Nation
    - Talking of Primates Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1981; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      International Journal of Primatology, G.A. Doyle, M. Cartmill
    - The Woman who never evolved Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1982; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Sarah Blaffer Hrdy, Amer. Scientist
    - Reproductive Biology of the Great Apes: Comparative and Biomedical Perspectives Author: AJ Princeton, 1982; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      C.E. Graham
    - A Life among the Chimpanzees Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1986; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Chimpanzees of Gombe, Jane Goodall, Natural History 95
    - Fildes, Breasts, Bottles and Babies: A History of Infant feeding Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1986; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      V. Fildes
    - Human Birth: An Evolutionary Perspective Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1987; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Wanda Trevathan, Medical Anthropology Quarterly
    - Woman of the Mists Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1988; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Farley Mowatt, New Scientist 15
    - How Monkeys see the World Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Dorothy L. Cheney, Robert M. Seyfarth, Science 251
    - Social Intelligence and Sexual Reproduction: Evolutionary Gambles Author: Alison Jolly Location: Santa Cruz, 1990; Manuscript typed (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Women's life history conference
    - Jantschke card Author: Fritz Jantschke Berenty, 1991; handwritten card (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Earthwatch
    - Primate Visions Author: Aj, MJ Princeton, 1991; reviews (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Donna Haraway, New Scientist 21, International Journal of Primatology Vol. 12, 1
    - Female Biology and Women Biologists Author: Alison Jolly Location: Santa Cruz, 1991; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Female Biology, Life History and Evolution conference, which provoked accusations of sexism because it was all women scientists
    - The Rise and Fall of the Third Chimpanzee Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Jared Diamond, BBC Wildlife
    - Walking with the Great Apes Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Sy Montgomery, Nature, Modern Shamans
    - Conscious Chimpanzees? A review of recent literature Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Cognitive Ethology: The minds of other animals, C. Ristau, P. Marler
    - Harsh Lessons in the art of suvival Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1992; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Focus 1:1, Drought, famine and targetting aggression
    - What really happened in Rio? Author: Alison Jolly Rio de Janeiro, 1993; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Laboratory Primate Newsletter 32:2
    - Missing Links, Visions of Caliban: On Chimpanzees and people Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1993; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Dale Peterson, Jane Goodall, Nature 362
    - Reinventing the future: conversations with the world's leading scientists Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1993; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Thomas A. Bass
    - Territoriality in Lemur Catta groups during the birth season Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1993; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Rasamimanana, M.F. Kinnaird, T.G. O'Brien, H.M. Crowley, C.S. Harcourt, S. Gardner, J.M. Davidson, Lemur Social Systems and their Ecological Basis
    - How to see lemurs Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1995; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Lemurs of Madagascar, Conservation International Tropical Field Guide Series, Russ Mittermeier, Ian Tattersall, W.R. Konstant, David M. Meyers, R.B. Mast, Amer. J. Primatol 39
    - Whistling Apes and Talking Drums Author: Alison Jolly Location: Zaire, 1995; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      BBC Wildlife Feb 1995 Theory of the origins of language by accretion from simpler codes
    - Presidents Corner Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1995; newsletter (Box 3, Folder 2)
      IPS newsletter
    - International Primatological Society Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1996; letters (Box 3, Folder 2)
      election of next president and council.
    - Maternal Responses to Dead and Dying Infants in Wild Troops of Ring-tailed Lemurs Author: AJ Berenty, 1996; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Masayuki Nakamichi, Naoki Koyama, International Journal of Primatology volume 17, 4
    - Why is sex fun? The evolution of human sexuality Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1997; review and letter (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Jared Diamond, Nature 388:532
    - Bonobo, The Forgotton Ape Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1997; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Frans de Waal, Frans Lanting, International Journal of Primatol 18
    - Pair-bonding, Female Aggression and the Evolution of Lemur Societies Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1998; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Folia Primatol 69
    - Machiavellian Intelligence 11. Extensions and evaluations Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1998; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Andrew Whiten, Pichard W. Byrne, Animal Cognition
    - Remaking Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly, 1998; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Virginia Morell, National Geographic
    - A Brief History of Conservation in Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1998; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      On the Edge, Madagscar: A World Apart, Wildlife Preservation Trust
    - Troop histories and range inertia of Lemur catta at Berenty, Madagascar: a 33 year perspective Author: AJ Princeton, 1999; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      International Journal of Primatology 20: 3 persistence of female-held tertitories
    - Alison Jolly Author: Caroline Moseley Location: Princeton, 1990s?; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Princeton Weekly Bulletin on Alison Jolly
    - IPS Newsletter, Presidents corner Location: Princeton, 1990s - 2001; newsletters (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Strasbourg, Free third world membership, Peterson and Goodall 'Visions of Caliban', Virunga gorillas, sulawesi, CAMP meeting, Berthe Rakotosamimanana, CITES, Toshisada Nishida: Madagascar Conference, camp meeting notes with Ulysses Seal, Russ Mittermeier et al.
    - Pitching it right: Observing chimps and the women who observe chimps Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 2000; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Africa in my blood: An autobiography in letters, Jane Goodall, Beauty and the Beasts: Woman, Ape and Evolution, Carole Jahme
    - The Fifth Step Author: AJ Lewes, 2000; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
      New Scientist, future world organism
    - Battlefield Sociobiology Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2000; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Defenders of the Truth, Ullica Segerstrale, Science 288:2137
    - Infant Killing, Wounding and Predation in Eulemur and Lemur Author: AJ, S.Caless, S. Cavigelli, L. Gould, M.Epereira, A. Pitts, R.E. Pride, H.D. Rabenandrasana, J.D. Walker, T. Zafison Berenty, 2000; article, paper (Box 3, Folder 3)
      International Journal of Primatology 21: 1, Bob Sussman objected to calling it "infanticide" but infant killing was OK
    - Keep Me Author: AJ Lewes, 2000; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Mother Nature: Natural Selection and the female of the species, Sarah Hrdy, London Review of Books 10 August
    - Monkeys in the Back Garden Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2001; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Science 291: 1705-1706
    - Love at Goon Park: Harry Harlow and the Science of Affection Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 2002; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Deborah Blum, Nature 420:741
    - Diary Author: AJ Berenty, 2003; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
      London Review of Books 21 January 2003, 40-41
    - Sick as a Parrot Author: Alison Jolly and V. Curtis Lewes, 2003; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Wild Health, C. Engel, London Review of Books 10 July 2003, 29